A Guide to the Lawrence Douglas Wilder campaign papers, 1976-1992
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lawrence Douglas Wilder campaign papers, 1976-1992
The Library of Virginia
53078
3 cu. ft. (8 boxes)
Lawrence Douglas Wilder
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from State Records collection.
Biographical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
Scope and Content
Campaign papers, 1976-1992, of Lawrence Douglas Wilder of Richmond, Virginia, containing articles, brochures, correspondence, financial records, invitations,
Arrangement
This collection is arranged
Series I: Elections, 1976-1985
Series II: Wilder for Governor, 1988-1989
Series III: Wilder for Governor, 1990-1992
Contents List
- Series I: Elections, 1976-1985., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  Elections, 1976-1992, contains advertisements, brochures, clippings, ephemera, magazines, newsletters, policy statements, press releases, reports, and other papers relating to presidential, congressional, and statewide office elections in Virginia.
  - Presidential, 1976.
    - Clippings: The Presidential Candidates' Positions on the Issues: How They Stand (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Delegates to the Democratic Convention (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Statewide offices, 1977.
    - Democratic candidates--papers (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Papers and correspondence (chiefly Gordon C. Morse) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Henry Howell statement, 8 September 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, April, June 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, August-October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, November 1977 (including results) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Senate, 1978.
    - Democratic party--papers (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, November 1977-June 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, September-October 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, no date (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Presidential, 1980.
    - Papers (including correspondence of Gordon C. Morse) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Congressional Quarterly, October 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, July 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, Charlottesville newspapers, 5 November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 5 November 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 26 October 1979, 2 August 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - U.S. Senate, 1982.
    - Paul Trible--papers (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Richard Davis--papers (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Democratic party--papers (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, March-August 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, September 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, October 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 3 November 1982 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 3 November 1982 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 4 November 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, November-December 1982, no date (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Presidential, 1984.
    - Ronald Reagan/George Bush--papers (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Walter Mondale--papers (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Geraldine Ferraro--papers (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Gary Hart--papers (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Congressional Quarterly: Guide to the 1984 Democratic Convention (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Governor, 1985.
    - Gerald Baliles campaign ephemera (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II: Wilder for Governor, 1988-1989., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 3-4)
  Wilder for Governor, 1988-1989, consists of correspondence, lists, and reports regarding contributions to Wilder's gubernatorial campaign, as well as a clipping, 15 October 1989, on the race.
  - Contribution lists and correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Contribution report, 27 April 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Contribution reports, 25-31 August 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Contribution reports, 2-8 September 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Contribution reports, 15-18 September 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Contribution reports, 2-5 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Contribution reports, 6-7 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Contribution reports, 9-10 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Contribution reports, 11-14 October 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Contribution reports, 17 October 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contribution reports, 19 October 1989 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Contribution reports, 19 October 1989 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Contribution reports, 20-23 October 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Contribution reports, 3-10 November 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Contribution reports, 13-14 November 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Clipping, 15 October 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series III: Wilder for President, 1990-1992., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 5-8)
  Wilder for President, 1990-1992, contains clippings, correspondence, directories, financial papers, invitations, stationery, ephemera, and other documents regarding Wilder's campaign for president in 1992.
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)